Once upon a time, there was a man who died.
The last story the man was writing was about a brave and handsome prince
who vanquishes a crafty raven.
When the man died, the raven and the prince escaped from within the story.
The prince took out his own heart to seal away the raven.
But this power, which had been granted solely to him, was nevertheless forbidden.
Thus sealed, the raven troubled them no more.
But the prince's heart was shattered and the shards scattered all over town.
Ever since then, stories and reality have intermingled in the town,
making it a world where the fantastical was no longer fantastical.
The andes
pensar
The
Andes
A dream? Where am I?
What am I doing here?
Quack!
Huh? What?
No way, no way, no way, no way, no way, no way, no way!
Quack. I'm just a duck.
And I thought I was a girl.
When I saved Senior Muto, was that a dream?
Quack, could this be a dream right now?
If you must know, neither is a dream, little duck.
How are you?
You may address me as Strasselmeyer.
Do you still want to save the poor prince who's lost his heart?
The person I want to save is Senior Muto.
The prince was a wholehearted hero who fought the demonic raven.
Well, he was when they were still inside the story.
Inside the story?
Yes. He came out of the story, I wrote, and ended up losing his heart to seal the raven away.
Shattered to pieces, his lost heart now wanders as a handful of shards.
And Princess Tutu is the only one who can restore his heart.
Princess... Tutu?
If you have the necessary resolve, I'll turn you into a girl once more.
A girl? I'll really get to see Senior Muto again?
If you have the resolve, that is?
I do! I do!
If I could be a girl again and stay by Senior Muto's side, maybe someday, someday I might be able to put a smile back on his face.
And if that's the one thing I can do, then there's nothing more that I could wish for.
Congratulations, dream, and your wish is granted. That's the great thing about stories. The duck will become a girl, and the girl will become Princess Tutu. Stories are such wonderful creatures. But remember this, if you say or do anything resembling a duck...
What?
You just remember that.
This is Gold Crown Town, and I'm...
Quack! A duck!
Quack, quack, quack, quack, quack, quack, quack, quack, quack, quack!
I am a duck.
So, Senior Muto and the Prince were all a dream.
Of course.
It's so calming to be on the water.
Quack!
If you say or do anything resembling a duck...
Oh, this is...
It wasn't a dream.
Huh?
May those who accept their fate be granted happiness.
May those who defy it be granted glory.
Who's that?
I am Adel.
You are a duck.
You know about me?
Even as a girl, you still have some duck-like qualities about you, don't you?
What?
The way you look.
The way I look?
Think of it as having had all your feathers plucked out.
These are for you.
So, if I am a duck as in the bird, since when was the girl me, the me that I am?
Or rather, yesterday me and two days ago me, and the me before that are all me, so...
Great!
Now I'm really lost!
A story's birth is a sudden event.
The start, a happy accident.
The end, the fate for which it's meant.
A story that never ends is a cruel thing.
I'm afraid you lost me too, Miss Adel.
Let us meet again.
Yes.
Oh well, oh well, oh well, oh well.
You're not partir!
Overall, Mathで both arms
Manuel!
Senior Meworu.
I turned into Princess Tutu
and saved Senior Meworu, right?
I wonder if he remembers.
Even if he did, he wouldn't people know, it was me.
Oh, what if he found out I was a duck, like the actual bird?
A duck? You're the worst. No wonder you talk like a duck. Shoo, shoo.
Or, man, you stink like a bird.
Or, my favorite, let's dig in.
I'll keep it a secret.
Senior Mewto, that thing about the prince who lost his heart.
Oh, I haven't made him an apology for his leg yet.
I must go.
Will you see? I'm so sorry.
What?
Your leg. Is your leg still hurting you?
Not really.
So it's all better now? Thank goodness.
I have to say something.
You reading a book?
Of course he is. Look, what am I saying?
You like books, then?
Oh, great. I'm a snob.
Is the book interesting?
Of course it is. He wouldn't read it if it wasn't.
Not really.
Huh?
I don't know if I particularly like or dislike books.
There they are again. Those lonely eyes.
Good day, Mewto.
Oh, hi, Rue.
Quack!
Wow.
Ant-eater? The animal that eats ants?
Why an ant-eater?
Okay, I'm a duck, but...
May I take a seat next to you?
Sure.
What exactly are your thoughts on Miss Rue?
I don't know.
You do love her, don't you?
Not really.
Then might I ask you to be with me instead?
Would you be averse to it?
Not really.
No way!
Mewto.
Oh, she licked him!
Ah!
Excuse me.
Quack!
You can't come this way!
I can't do this as a duck.
How do I go back to being a girl?
Oh, what did you last time?
That's right.
Water!
Quack!
I did it, Rue!
Ah!
I can't go out naked like this.
Now what?
Oh, oh, quack!
Hey, um, um, look at me!
Oh, my!
But is it Miss Rue?
Huh?
Uh...
Please allow me the pleasure of informing you that Miyuto is going to accompany me now.
What?
It seems quite clear who the winner is here.
Excuse us.
Uh...
No, no, don't listen to her!
I'm pretty sure it's not true!
That wasn't for real, so it's...
Doesn't bother me.
What?
Thank you, though.
You're so sweet.
Huh?
I...
What?
With Aunt in Arena?
Are all people?
Oh, my God!
What?
Need you ask?
Dumping Rue like that?
You're terrible.
Am I really?
Because you don't understand how people feel.
It's why you do things like that without a thought.
I'm sorry.
Idiot.
That's how it should be.
With ballet, take a day off and you will know.
Take three days off and your peers will know.
Take a week off and the audience will know.
As this adage aptly demonstrates, daily practice is of the utmost importance.
And so, we will have a test once a month from now on to assign you to a class.
In the worst case, you'll be dropped to the probationary class.
What?
Probation?
That or I will have you marry me.
What?
No way!
Hmm?
No?
No way?
Mr. Cat!
What?
Miss Aunt in Arena?
This special class is strictly capped at five.
Yes?
So?
Then I suppose someone will have to be dropped to make room for me.
A declaration of war!
Taking not just her lover, but her status too.
How exciting!
To prove my worthiness, I shall dance a potty-do with my partner.
Come, Mewtwo!
Oh, what?
Wow, an even more exciting turn of events!
This can't be!
Guess it wasn't all talk, huh?
Now, a woman's battle.
She's definitely good, but somehow there's no joy in it.
Ms. Roo, I would very much like to see your pas de deux, but whether or not there is an actual partner for you...
That was mean.
Roo is in a pinch.
A pinch.
Huh?
Would you dance with me?
What?
Huh?
Me?
That's right.
Roo, you know, I'm really terrible at this, so I don't think I'm going to be any good to you at all.
Don't worry.
Just follow my directions, all right?
Don't be nervous.
Oh, okay.
But just she messes up.
Yeah.
A storm's brewing.
Now jump.
Huh?
Ah!
You were wonderful.
Mimi, it's almost like she wasn't duck.
You're right.
I wasn't duck at all.
You think nothing of the humiliation
that I, your girlfriend, just went through?
Not really.
Did you not do your best on purpose?
I don't know.
Do not mock me!
Just so you are aware,
if you had not been Rue's boyfriend,
I would not have asked you out in the first place.
Goodbye!
Have you come to laugh at me?
No, I wouldn't.
Oh, wait, uh...
Leave me alone!
Uh, what's going on?
In an arena!
It's not fair!
Not fair!
I know.
Go on and cry.
It is unfair.
Oh, Senior Muto?
It's so unfair, it hurts!
Please stay with me!
Of course.
Wait, what is that?
I need you too, Auntie Darina.
I need your poor, broken heart.
Oh, that's...
Looks like you've found one of the shards of the Princess Lost Heart.
Now, reveal the mystery for me, Princess Tootoo.
Who are you?
Have you come to laugh at me as well?
No, Auntie Darina.
But the one next to you is not your partner.
Don't be absurd!
Please come dance with me, Auntie Darina.
I refuse!
You couldn't possibly understand how I feel!
Go away!
Auntie Darina!
Is that your way of dancing?
Yes!
To make your audience surrender!
That is art!
But that isn't how you really feel!
Oh, no!
I believe it from the bottom of my heart!
This is my way of dancing!
Then why?
Why do you seem to be in such pain?
There's no joy in your dancing!
None at all!
What are you so bitter about?
That!
How wonderful!
Please tell me, what must I do to dance so wonderfully?
I don't know.
Practice?
I'll work hard!
I'll work hard until I can dance that well, just like you, Miss Rue!
You can't.
It's not possible.
I want to beat Miss Rue!
To win by any means necessary!
Those feelings!
Those feelings are not truly yours, Auntie Darina!
Forget your bitterness and hatred!
I want to beat Miss Rue!
I want to see how you truly dance!
It will be much more beautiful!
Let us dance together!
To your heart's content!
Be honest!
Be free!
Yes!
This is truly your way of dancing!
I feel such joy!
You must be!
I'm the feeling of bitter disappointment, shattered and forgotten!
But this is not the place to which you belong!
Must I wander again?
You need to go back!
Can I go back?
Mm-hmm.
I'm the feeling of bitter disappointment, shattered and forgotten.
But this is not the place to which you belong.
Must I wander again?
You need to go back.
Can I go back?
Mm-hmm.
I know.
I'm so glad.
I really and truly have been able to become Princess Tutu.
Muto!
What's wrong, Muto?
What is this feeling? I don't understand.
A feeling?
Now then, the special class will be the same five people as before.
And Miss Auntie Tarina?
Yes?
Your performance was good, but the decision is to wait and see this time around.
Yes, understood.
I have decided to stop copying Miss Rue and find my own way of dancing.
I look forward to seeing it.
And as for Miss Duck...
Yes?
Your performance was also quite good.
However, you owe it entirely to Miss Rue.
Thus, you are assigned to the probationary class.
I knew it!
You must never forget that Duck is, after all, a duck.
Hehehehe!
Senior Mewto is actually a prince out of a story.
That must be why he's so handsome.
Rue, I love you.
It's Rue. I wonder if she knows.
Princess Tutu.
This is ridiculous. That's just a story.
Though blessed with beauty, cleverness, and strength,
she's still a princess fated never to be with her prince.
When she confesses her love, she turns into a speck of light and vanishes.
All who love stories gather round.
Rue, Rue, Rue.